commonsensemarketing.net 2011-11-25

# Privacy Policy | Common Sense Marketing

## [ Privacy Policy ](http://www.commonsensemarketing.net/privacy-policy/ "Permanent Link to Privacy Policy")

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Common Sense Marketing we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals: http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/

(Note, we’ve decided to make this privacy policy available under a Creative Commons Sharealike license, which means you’re more than welcome to steal it and repurpose it for your own use, just make sure to replace references to us with ones to you, and if you want we’d appreciate a link to our site somewhere on your site. We spent a lot of money and time on the below, and other people shouldn’t need to do the same.)

Common Sense Marketing is operated by New Arbor Enterprise. It is Common Sense Marketing’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Common Sense Marketing collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Common Sense Marketing’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Common Sense Marketing’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Common Sense Marketing may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Common Sense Marketing also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Common Sense Marketing does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Common Sense Marketing’s websites choose to interact with Common Sense Marketing in ways that require Common Sense Marketing to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Common Sense Marketing gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a newsletter to provide an email address. Those who engage in transactions with Common Sense Marketing are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Common Sense Marketing collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Common Sense Marketing. Common Sense Marketing does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Common Sense Marketing may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Common Sense Marketing may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Common Sense Marketing does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Common Sense Marketing discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Common Sense Marketing’s behalf or to provide services available at Common Sense Marketing’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Common Sense Marketing’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Common Sense Marketing will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Common Sense Marketing discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Common Sense Marketing believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Common Sense Marketing, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Common Sense Marketing website and have supplied your email address, Common Sense Marketing may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Common Sense Marketing and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Common Sense Marketing takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Common Sense Marketing uses cookies to help Common Sense Marketing identify and track visitors, their usage of Common Sense Marketing website, and their website access preferences. Common Sense Marketing visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Common Sense Marketing’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Common Sense Marketing’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Common Sense Marketing and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Common Sense Marketing may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Common Sense Marketing’s sole discretion. Common Sense Marketing encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Last updated: 12/2010

Contact us if you have questions about accessing or correcting your personal data.

Thank you to the folks at Automattic (makers of the WordPress blog platform) for sharing this Privacy Policy.
